# **Chandrakant Gopalan**

Github: http://github.com/cgopalan Ph: (716) 573-5671

Portfolio: http://cgopalan.github.io Email: chandrakant.gopalan@gmail.com

#### **Executive Summary**

Chandrakant Gopalan has a Bachelors in Engineering, and has worked in the software industry for more than 15 years. During his career, he has designed and developed a variety of applications using techniques like object-oriented and functional programming and has worked with data-intensive applications backed by databases like Postgres, MySQL and Oracle. He has been working with Python and C# since 2006, and has used it for a variety of applications like data analysis, data transformation and backends for web applications.

#### Languages & Technologies

Python 2.x/3.x, C#, PostgreSQL, MySQL, Oracle, MongoDB, Django, Flask, Redis, Git

## Ongoing projects/Contributions (More on github):

Bug fixes for Python api for sunlightlabs project, contributed documentation to postgresguide.com

## Online Courses / MOOCs (Certificates available on request):

Machine Learning (Stanford/Coursera), Algorithms I (Coursera), MongoDB for Python Developers (10gen),

#### **Work Experience**

Position: Software Engineer, Pinogy Corporation, Remote

Apr 2016 till date

- Continued work on a suite of batch programs in Python to take in vendor data in different formats like JSON, YAML and XML, transform it and insert into a Postgres database.

Position: Senior Backend Engineer, GoButler, NY

Aug 2015 - Apr 2016

- Part of a 3-member team that worked on developing the backend architecture with REST APIs to process sms and iOS messages using Django, MySQL, Redis and Celery on AWS.
- Developed a set of ETL scripts in SQL to extract data from MySQL and insert into a Postgres datawarehouse.

Position: Software Engineer, Sailthru, NY

Sep 2014 - July 2015

- Developed Python batch scripts with MongoDB as backend
- Developed web apps in Flask, and restful HTTP services in tornado

Position: Senior Software Engineer, Dealertrack Technologies, NY

May 2013 - Sep 2014

- Part of a team to design, develop a suite of applications for the automotive selling industry. The application led the consumer right from the process of choosing a vehicle to providing financing for the purchase. Used Python, Django, MongoDB, Redis and Oracle. Also did code reviews, approved pull requests and mentored junior Python developers.

Position: Software Engineer, Pinogy Corporation, Remote

Dec 2011 - May 2013

- Part of a team to design and develop a suite of batch programs to take in vendor data in different formats, transform it and insert into the PIDB database. Used Python for batch programs and Postgres for the database.

Position: Staff Engineer, Mindex Technologies, Rochester, NY Client: Paychex, Rochester, NY Oct 2009 - Dec 2011
Part of a team that developed a C#, ASP.NET application for managing healthcare and benefits for small businesses.

Position: Software Engineer, One Communications Inc, Rochester, NY

May 2006 - Oct 2009

Migrated about 2 million trouble tickets from the legacy system to the current system using C#, Oracle SQL, and python scripts.

### Education

Bachelor of Technology (Hons.) in Energy Engineering, Indian Institute of Technology (IIT), Kharagpur, India